Exercise 10-1. Comparing OO and UH. Look at the chart that follows and repeat each
word. We're contrasting the sound OO, first and third columns, a strong, non
-reducible sound, OO, that is made far forward in the mouth, with the lips fully
rounded, with the reduced UH sound in the second and fourth columns. 1. Booed. Book.
2. Boo. Bushel. 3. Cooed. Could. 4. Cool. Cushion. 5. Food. Foot. 6. Fool. Full. 7.
Goode. Good. 8. Hoode. Hood. 9. Cooke. Cook. 10. Crew. Crook. 11. Luke. Look. 12.
Nuke. Nook. 13. Pool. Pull. 14. Pooch. Putt. Fifteen. Shoe. Sugar. Sixteen. Suit.
Sit. Seventeen. Shoot. Should. Eighteen. Stewed. Stood. Nineteen. Toucan. Took.
Twenty. Wooed. Wood. For the OO sound, round your lips like a fish. For the OO
sound, Think of a chicken. Chickens don't have lips so they certainly can't round
them. You have to say, uh, down in the back of your throat.